Guide to the Holly Schepisi and Paul Garfinkel Collection of Photographs 1945-1985 PR 381
New-York Historical Society
Holly Schepisi and Paul Garfinkel collection of photographs
1945-1985
New-York Historical Society
Garfinkel, Paul C.
PR 381
2 Linear feet in 2 boxes
This collection, assembled and donated by Holly Schepisi and Paul Garfinkel, consists of photographs from three discrete photographers/photo agencies: the Black Star Agency's images of prominent people and events (1975-1984); André de Dienes' portraits of Marilyn Monroe (1945-1953); and photojournalist Ken Regan's images of the ABC-TV newsroom (1981-1983) and the Kennedy family (1971-1985).
Access Restrictions
Open to qualified researchers by appointment only.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Holly Schepisi and Paul Garfinkel, 2014.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in three series by photographer:
Series I: Black Star Agency photographs
Series II: André de Dienes photographs
Series III: Ken Regan photographs
Each series is organized alphabetically by subject.
Scope and Contents
This collection, assembled and donated by Holly Schepisi and Paul Garfinkel, consists of photographs from three discrete photographers/photo agencies.
The first set of photographs is from the Black Star Agency, and contains images of prominent people and events of the 1970s and 1980s. Photos include actors such as Farrah Fawcett, Richard Gere, and Diane Keaton; political figures including President Jimmy Carter, Anwar Sadat, and Menachem Begin; and royals including Prince Charles, Princess Diana, and Princess Caroline of Monaco.
A second set of photos are portraits of Marilyn Monroe dated 1945-1953, taken by André de Dienes. These portraits are accompanied by certificates of authenticity from the curator and manager of the de Dienes archive.
The final set are photographs by photojournalist Ken Regan, including behind the scenes images of ABC News broadcasts, 1981-1983, and photographs of the extended Kennedy family at work, at political and social events, and at the family compound, 1971-1985. Most of these images are of Ted Kennedy, though there are also photos of Jackie Kennedy Onassis, John F. Kennedy Jr., Caroline Kennedy, Joe Kennedy Jr., and Pat Lawford.
Biographical / Historical
The Black Star Agency was founded in 1935 by German Jewish refugees Kurt Safranski, Ernest Mayer and Kurt Kornfeld, who fled Berlin during the Nazi regime. They were innovators in Germany's picture press and publishing world, and brought with them a wealth of knowledge about photography and photojournalism. Their New York-based agency commissioned and brokered the use of photographs that documented important events, people of note, and human interest stories. One of their first major clients was Henry Luce's Life magazine, founded in 1936. In 1964, the company was sold to Howard Chapnick, a photographer who had joined the agency after his service in WWII. He led the agency for the next 25 years.
Ken Regan (d. 2012) worked for over five decades documenting pop culture, sports, foreign conflicts, and other current events. Credited with over 200 magazine covers, Regan was most well-known for a discretion and professionalism which earned him intimate shooting access to famous politicians, musicians, and other celebrities. Regan also covered major events for magazines such as Time, Sports Illustrated, Life, and Newsweek. In the 1970s he founded Camera 5, an agency of 15 photographers who covered wars, riots and demonstrations, and other national and international hard news and human interest stories.
André de Dienes (1913-1985) was a Hungarian American fashion photographer best known for his early portraits of the actress Marilyn Monroe.
Celebrities -- Portraits; Politicians.; Black Star (Picture agency); De Dienes, André, 1913-1985; Regan, Ken; Schepisi, Holly
- Series I: Black Star Agency photographs, 1975-1984
  Scope and Contents
  contains images of prominent people and events of the 1970s and 1980s.
  - Portraits A-B, 1975-1983 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Woody Allen
    Ann-Margret
    Julie Anderson
    Yuri Andropov
    Yasser Arafat
    Desi Arnaz Jr.
    Brigitte Bardot
    Mikhail Baryshnikov
    Patricia Bellwood
    Candace Bergen
    Marlon Brando
    Jerry Brown
  - Portraits C-D, 1977-1984 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Shakira Caine
    Jimmy Carter and family
    Fidel Castro
    Cyd Charisse
    Joan Collins
    Francis Ford Coppola
    Patti Davis
    Deng Xiaoping
    Bo Derek
    Ana De Sade
    Angie Dickinson
    Robert Duvall
  - Portraits E-G, 1977-1983 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Blake Edwards
    Morgan Fairchild (with Prince Alberto of Monaco)
    Farrah Fawcett
    Jane Fonda
    Jodie Foster
    Richard Gere
    Indira Gandhi (with Prince Charles)
    Mel Gibson
    Princess Caroline Grimaldi of Monaco
    Princess Stephanie Grimaldi of Monaco
    Andrei Gromyko
  - Portraits H-L, 1977-1984 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Charlton Heston
    Finola Hughes
    Diane Keaton
    Kennedy Family
    Ayatollah Khomeini
    Ed Koch
    Jerry Lewis
  - Portraits M-N, 1977-1982 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Shirley Maclaine
    Norman Mailer
    Francois Mitterand
    Walter Mondale
    Dudley Moore
    Mary Tyler Moore
    Roger Moore
    Ed Muskie
    Paul Newman with Joanne Woodward
    Ralph Nader
    Jack Nicholson
    Richard Nixon
  - Portraits O-R, 1978-1983 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Laurence Olivier
    Christina Onassis
    Jackie Kennedy Onassis with Caroline Kennedy and JFK Jr.
    Tatum O'Neal
    Richard Pryor
    Eden Pastora [Nicaraguan political figure]
    Ronald and Nancy Reagan with Ron Reagan
    Ginger Rogers
  - Portraits S-Z, 1978-1984 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Tom Selleck
    Jane Seymour
    Brooke Shields
    Sylvester Stallone
    Rod Steiger
    Meryl Streep
    Barbra Streisand
    Mother Teresa
    Heather Thomas
    Lily Tomlin
    John Travolta
    Linn Ullman
    John Wayne
    Orson Welles
    Mae West
  - British Royal Family, 1977-1983 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Prince Andrew
    Prince Charles
    Prince Edward
    Prince Philip
    Prince William
    Princess Anne
    Princess Diana
    Queen Elizabeth
    *includes wedding photos of Prince Charles and Princess Diana
  - Egypt-Israel Peace Treaty, 1977-1979 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    images of President Anwar Sadat of Egypt, Prime Minister Menachem Begin of Israel, and U.S. President Jimmy Carter, and U.S. Secretary of State Cyrus Vance during the peace negotiations between Egypt and Israel.
  - Vietnam Veterans, 1981-1983 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    photos of people, including veterans, visiting the Vietnam Veterans Memorial Wall in Washington D.C. One photo of an injured Vietnam veteran running a marathon.
- Series II: André de Dienes photographs, 1945-1953
  14 images of Marilyn Monroe. Also includes certificates of authenticity from the curator and manager of the de Dienes archive, Chuck Murphy.
  - Marilyn Monroe, 1945-1953 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Series III: Ken Regan photographs, 1971-1985
  - ABC News Broadcasting, 1981-1983 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    behind the scenes images of ABC News.
  - Kennedy Family, 1971-1985 (Box 2, Folder 6-9)
    photographs of the extended Kennedy family at work, at political and social events, and at the family compound. Most of the images are of Ted Kennedy. Also included are photos of Jackie Kennedy Onassis, John F. Kennedy Jr., Caroline Kennedy, Joe Kennedy Jr., and Pat Lawford.